SARAH PROCTOR

WEB DEVELOPMENT INSTRUCTOR

CONTACT

- sarah@learnacademy.org
- San Diego, CA
- github.com/sjproctor
- in /in/sarah-proctor-sd

EDUCATION

LEARN Academy

Full-stack Web Development San Diego, CA | 2018

Boise State University

Credits towards Psychology, B.S. Boise, ID | 2008

TECH SKILLS

- JavaScript
- React
- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- HTML/CSS
- Bootstrap / Reactstrap
- Jest / Enzyme
- RSpec
- GitHub / git

INTERESTS

Yoga, Running, Narrative Nonfiction Audiobooks, Hiking, Baking, Patio Gardening

ABOUT ME

Passion for creating a welcoming learning environment that invites all students to explore the wonder of creating software regardless of background or previous experience in technology. Using clear communication to curate a brave space of honesty and empathy while empowering students to harness their unique learning styles and creativity. Advocate for ethical technology and creating clean, concise code that communicates intention above all.

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPMENT INSTRUCTOR AND STUDENT AFFAIRS COORDINATOR

LEARN ACADEMY | SAN DIEGO, CA | 2018 - PRESENT

Head instructor at a four-month full-stack web development bootcamp. Creating an immersive, challenging, and supportive learning environment for cohorts of 10-14 adult students to learn fundamentals of programming and development.

- Managing and overseeing a three-person instruction team
- Creating and delivering lectures with live coding demonstrations ranging from basic introductions to authentication and authorization in a full-stack application
- Creating organizational systems to manage concurrent classrooms, internal projects, community events, extracurricular learning and wellness activities
- Technical curriculum development, continuous addition and review of content
- Implemented a standardization of syllabus formatting and presentation
- Creating coding challenges, projects, and mock interview practical questions

VOLUNTEER

GIRLS IN TECH

LEADERSHIP COMMITTEE | SAN DIEGO, CA | 2019 - PRESENT

Organizing and staffing volunteer events such as *Hacking for Humanity*, *San Diego Tech Women's Summit*, and *Learn to Code* for the San Diego chapter of Girls in Tech, a global non-profit organization.

SD RUBY

CO-ORGANIZER | SAN DIEGO, CA | 2019 - PRESENT

Recruiting and scheduling speakers, organizing and ordering supplies for the monthly meetup of the Ruby community in San Diego.